Folio Society Collection
Folio Society Collection
1895-1968
Folio Society (London, England)
3 linear ft.
Correspondence with authors, editors, and artists; original artwork; unbound galleys for FOLIO 21: A bibliography of The Folio Society 1947-1967
4945457
Biographical History
The Folio Society is a privately owned London-based publisher, founded by Charles Ede, Christopher Sandford, and Alan Bott in 1947. It produces illustrated hardback editions of classic fiction and non-fiction books, poetry and children's titles. For many years the Society also operated a bookstore in the Holborn area of London, but it closed in 2016.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Folio Society Collection consists of correspondence with authors, editors, and illustrators, as well as numerous pieces of original art including wood block prints, lithographs, and sketches. Notable correspondents include Cecil Beaton, Walter de la Mare, Daphne du Maurier, Derrick Harris, Joan Hassall, Gerard Hopkins, B.H. Liddell Hart, Harold Nicolson, Laurence Olivier, Herbert Beerbohm Tree, and Cicely Veronica Wedgwood.
The material is arranged by Folio Society publication number, although not all Folio Society publications are represented, and in some cases correspondence or artwork pertaining to one publication may be filed under another title due to context. The Society's own bibliography, a copy of which is in the collection, was used to determine dates. Under each publication are listed the names of the correspondents and/or artists represented in that folder. In addition, a complete Index to the collection is provided at the end of this finding aid.
Arrangement of the Collection
By Folio Society publication number (FS 1, FS 2, etc.), according to the Society's bibliography.
Related Material
also has a large collection of more than 350 Folio Society editions. Please refer to to locate these items.
Subject and Genre Headings
Publishing, printing and book arts; Literature -- American Fiction; Literature -- American Poetry; Literature -- British; Literature -- French; Beaton, Cecil, 1904-1980.; Birkett, Norman Birkett, Baron, 1883-1962.; Bonfils, Robert, 1886-1972.; Boullaire, Jacques, 1893-1976.; Buckland Wright, John, 1897-1954.; Ede, Charles.; Einzig, Susan.; Gibbings, Robert, 1889-1958.; Goor, G. (Gaston), 1902-1977.; Harris, Derrick, 1919-1960.; Hassall, Joan.; Hopkins, Gerard, 1892-1961.; Le Campion, Valentin.; Martin, Frank, 1921-2005.; Olivier, Laurence, 1907-1989.; Palmer, Garrick.; Peake, Mervyn, 1911-1968.; Read, Harold Hope.; Rossem, Ru van.; Sala Grau, Joan, 1938-; Stone, Reynolds.; Svolinský, Karel, 1896-1986.; Whyte, Edna.; Folio Society (London, England); FOLIO 21: A bibliography of The Folio Society 1947-1967.; Authors, English.; Authors, American.; Authors, French.; Classical literature -- Publishing.; Literature publishing -- Great Britain -- History -- 20th century.; Private presses -- England.; Publishers and publishing -- Great Britain.; Correspondence.; Engravings (prints); Lithographs.; Sketches.; Woodcuts (prints)
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, 1969.
Inventory
- Bibliographies and lists
  - FOLIO 21: A bibliography of The Folio Society 1947-1967, 1968; unbound proof with handwritten annotations by unknown person (Box 1)
- 1947 publications
  - FS 2 Trilby / George du Maurier, 1895; 1947-1948 (Box 1)
    du Maurier, Daphne, 9 Feb 1947
    Sadleir, Michael, 29 Apr 1947
    Sadleir, Michael, 2 Jun 1947
    Sadleir, Michael, 11 Feb 1948
    Tree, Herbert Beerbohm, [1895?], theatre program for Trilby
  - FS 4 The Sonnets / William Shakespeare, 1948 (Box 1)
    Stone, Reynolds, 20 May 1948
  - FS 6 Confessions of an English Opium-Eater / Thomas de Quincey, 1963 (Box 1)
    Hughes-Stanton, Blair, 20 Jan 1963
- 1948 publications
  - FS 8 The Voyages of Lemuel Gulliver / Jonathan Swift, 1947 (Box 1)
    Bawden, Edward, 17 Jul 1947
    Bawden, Edward, 30 Oct 1947
  - FS 10 The Crime of Sylvestre Bonnard / Anatole France, undated (Box 1)
    Read, H. Hope, 14 lithographs for Crime of Sylvestre Bonnard
    Read, H. Hope, Oct 12
  - FS 11 The Odyssey / Homer, 1947-1948 (Box 1)
    Buckland-Wright, John, 10 Nov 1948
    Buckland-Wright, John, 16 engravings (artist's proofs) and one drawing (pencil and pen) for The Odyssey
    Lucas, F.L., 23 Jun 1947
    Lucas, F.L., 13 Mar 1948
  - FS 12 Dr Jekyll and Mr Hyde / Robert Louis Stevenson, 1949 (Box 1)
    Peake, Mervyn, 22 Feb 1949
- 1949 publications
  - FS 13 The School for Scandal / Richard Sheridan, 1948-1949 (Box 1)
    Beaton, Cecil, rough sketch for School for Scandal
    Beaton, Cecil, 1948
    Beaton, Cecil, 20 Aug 1948
    Olivier, Sir Laurence, 25 Jan 1949
  - FS 15 The Compleat Angler / Izaak Walton, 1948-1949 (Box 1)
    Lamb, Lynton, 14 Sep 1948
    Lamb, Lynton, 4 Jan 1949
  - FS 17 The Parson's Daughter and Other Stories / Anthony Trollope, 1948; undated (Box 1)
    Hassall, Joan, 27 Jul 1948
    Hassall, Joan, 22 Dec 1948
    Hassall, Joan, sketch and woodcut for Parson's Daughter (in book itself, which has been sent to cataloging; please refer to to locate this item)
  - FS 19 Poems / Percy Bysshe Shelley, 1949; undated (Box 1)
    Buckland-Wright, John, 28 wood engravings on one sheet for Shelley
    Church, Richard, 1 Mar 1949
- 1950 publications
  - FS 22 The History of Henry Esmond / William Makepeace Thackeray, undated (Box 1)
    Clarke Hutton, Thomas, one drawing and two lithographs for Henry Esmond
  - FS 24 Salambo / Gustave Flaubert, 1949-1950 (Box 1)
    Rossem, Ru van, 17 Mar 1949
    Rossem, Ru van, 4 Apr 1950
    Rossem, Ru van, pen sketch and ten engravings for Salambo
  - FS 26 The Iliad / Homer, 1950 (Box 1)
    Buckland-Wright, John, 9 engravings (artist's proofs) for The Iliad
    Lucas, F.L., 5 Jul 1950
  - FS 27 The Tragedy of Romeo and Juliet / William Shakespeare, 1949-1950 (Box 1)
    Coghill, Nevill, [1950s?]
    Hugo, Jean, 21 Apr 1949
  - FS 29 Manon Lescaut / Antoine-Francois Prevost, 1950; undated (Box 1)
    Le Campion, Valentin, 28 Feb 1950
    Le Campion, Valentin, 21 Nov 1950
    Le Campion, Valentin, 23 wood engravings for Manon
    Sackville-West, Edward, 28 Jan 1950
  - FS 30 Typee / Herman Melville, 1948-1951 (Box 1)
    Boullaire, Jacques, 6 Oct 1948
    Boullaire, Jacques, 27 Oct 1948
    Boullaire, Jacques, 5 Aug 1950
    Boullaire, Jacques, 1 Jun 1951
    Boullaire, Jacques, one etching for Typee
    Gibbings, Robert, 24 Feb 1950
    Gibbings, Robert, 20 Mar 1950
    Gibbings, Robert, 2 Dec 1950
- 1951 publications
  - FS 31 Incognita / William Congreve, [1950] (Box 1)
    Rossem, Ru van, [1950]
  - FS 33 The Tragedy of Macbeth / William Shakespeare, 1949-1951; 1964 (Box 1)
    Ayrton, Michael, 14 Nov 1949
    Ayrton, Michael, 14 Aug 1964
    Casson, Sir Lewis, 13 Dec 1950
    Casson, Sir Lewis, 4 Apr 1951
  - FS 35 Letters / Horace Walpole, 1951 (Box 1)
    Ketton-Cremer, R.W., 10 Jun 1951
    Lewis, Wilmarth S., 27 Jun 1951
  - FS 36 Some People / Sir Harold Nicolson, 1949-1950 (Box 1)
    Nicolson, Harold, 5 Feb 1949
    Nicolson, Harold, 21 Apr 1950
    Nicolson, Harold, 26 May 1950
    Nicolson, Harold, [1950], pen sketch
  - FS 37 Mary Gresley and Other Stories / Anthony Trollope, 1951 (Box 1)
    Hassall, Joan, 30 Mar 1951
    Hassall, Joan, 3 Aug 1951
  - FS 40 The Newgate Calendar / Sir Norman Birkett (ed.), 1950-1951 (Box 1)
    Birkett, Sir Norman, 14 Nov 1950
    Birkett, Sir Norman, 3 Mar 1951
    Birkett, Sir Norman, 16 Apr 1951
    Birkett, Sir Norman, 27 May 1951
  - FS 41 The Sofa / Claude-Prosper Jolyot de Crebillon, 1950 (Box 1)
    Bonfils, Robert, 9 Oct 1950
    Bonfils, Robert, one drawing and seven engravings for The Sofa
- 1952 publications
  - FS 43 The Vicar of Wakefield / Oliver Goldsmith, undated (Box 1)
    Wetherbee, Margaret, drawing for Vicar of Wakefield
  - FS 44 Madame Bovary / Gustave Flaubert, 1951 (Box 1)
    Sala Grau, Joan, 4 Sep 1951
    Sala Grau, Joan, 28 Oct 1951
    Sala Grau, Joan, 12 engravings for Madame Bovary
  - FS 45 Memoirs of Prince Alexy Haimatoff / Thomas Jefferson Hogg, 1952 (Box 1)
    Bliss, Douglas Percy, 15 Apr 1952
    Bliss, Douglas Percy, 29 Oct 1952
    Scott, W. Sidney, 10 Apr 1952
  - FS 46 The Tragedy of Antony and Cleopatra / William Shakespeare, 1951-1952 (Box 1)
    Olivier, Sir Laurence, 2 Jun 1951
    Olivier, Sir Laurence, 31 Jul 1951
    Olivier, Sir Laurence, 15 Jan 1952
  - FS 47 The Quest for Corvo / A.J.A. Symons, undated (Box 1)
    Hartz, Sam, engraving for Quest for Corvo
  - FS 50 Two Tales of the Congo / Joseph Conrad, 1951 (Box 1)
    Rieser, Dolf, 14 Sep 1951
- 1953 publications
  - FS 56 Joseph Andrews / Henry Fielding, 1952 (Box 1)
    Harris, Derrick, 30 Mar 1952
    Harris, Derrick, 1 Oct 1952
  - FS 57 Eastern Love Poems / Powys Mathers (trans.), 1952 (Box 1)
    Rossem, Ru van, 14 Dec 1952
  - FS 58 In the Beginning / Norman Douglas, undated (Box 1)
    Sharp, Richard, pen sketch
  - FS 61 Louis XIV at Versailles / Louis de Rouvroy, 1952 (Box 1)
    Goor, 21 Aug 1952
    Goor, color sketch for Louis XIV
  - FS 62 Readings from Dickens / Emyln Williams, 1953 (Box 1)
    Darwin, Bernard, 4 Apr 1953
    Williams, Emlyn, 13 Oct 1953
  - FS 63 The Young King and Other Stories / Oscar Wilde, 1951 (Box 1)
    Gaastra, John, color sketch for Young King
    Holland, Vyvyan, 16 Mar 1951
- 1954 publications
  - FS 64 Drake's Raid on the Treasure Trains / John and Janet Hampden (eds.), 1953 (Box 1)
    Wales, Geoffrey, 4 Mar 1953
  - FS 65 Moll Flanders / Daniel Defoe, 1953 (Box 1)
    Lambourne, Nigel, 7 Feb 1953
    Lambourne, Nigel, 20 Jun 1953
    Lambourne, Nigel, 20 Jun 1953, with sketch
    Lambourne, Nigel, sketch with notes for Moll Flanders
  - FS 71 The Tragedy of Hamlet, Prince of Denmark / William Shakespeare
    - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 1)
      Burton, Richard, 27 Mar 1954
    - Artwork (Oversize 1)
      Roger Furse, oversize drawing of Laurence Olivier as Hamlet
  - FS 72 Sappho / Alphonse Daudet, undated (Box 1)
    Einzig, Susan, 8 engravings for Sappho
  - FS 74, 76 The Decameron: The First Five Days & The Second Five Days / Giovanni Boccaccio, 1953-1954 (Box 1)
    Buckland-Wright, John, 19 Dec 1953
    Buckland-Wright, John, 10 May 1954
    Buckland-Wright, John, 20 engravings for The Decameron
- 1955 publications
  - FS 75 The Discovery of Tahiti / George Robertson, 1953 (Box 1)
    Gibbings, Robert, 4 Dec 1953
    Gibbings, Robert, ten wood engravings
  - FS 76 The Decameron: The The Second Five Days / Giovanni Boccaccio, See 1954 publications: FS 74, 76 The Decameron: The First Five Days & The Second Five Days.
  - FS 78 Humphry Clinker / Tobias Smollett, 1954 (Box 1)
    Harris, Derrick, 11 Jul 1954
    Harris, Derrick, drawing for Humphrey Clinker
  - FS 80 Bel-Ami / Guy de Maupassant, 1954 (Box 1)
    Grant, Alistair, 30 Nov 1954
  - FS 81 Othello / William Shakespeare, 1952; 1955 (Box 1)
    Moiseiwitsch, Tanya, 25 Jul 1955
    Welles, Orson, 23 Jan 1952
  - FS 84 The Virgin and the Gypsy / David Herbert Lawrence, undated (Box 1)
    Masterman, Dodie, 5 engravings for Virgin and the Gypsy (not used)
  - FS 86 The Semi-Attached Couple / Emily Eden, 1954 (Box 1)
    Braby, Dorothea, 18 Mar 1954
- 1956 publications
  - FS 87 Memoirs of Madame du Barry / Mathieu-Francois Pidansat de Mairobert, 1955 (Box 1)
    Flint, Sir William Russell, 19 Mar 1955
  - FS 88 The Woman in White / Wilkie Collins, 1961 (Box 1)
    Lamb, Lynton, 26 Jan 1961
  - FS 89 The Bridge of San Luis Rey / Thornton Wilder, undated (Box 1)
    Martin, Frank, wood engravings for Bridge of San Luis Rey
  - FS 91 The Confessional of the Black Penitents / Ann Radcliffe, 1955 (Box 1)
    Ross, Philip E., 21 Feb 1955
  - FS 92 The Young Visiters [sic], or, Mr Salteena's Plan / Daisy Ashford, 1955 (Box 1)
    Brough, Diana, 14 Feb 1955
  - FS 93 The Tragedy of King Lear / William Shakespeare, 1953; 1956 (Box 1)
    Wolfit, Donald, 9 Dec 1953
    Wolfit, Donald, 12 Mar 1956
    Wolfit, Donald, 16 Mar 1956
  - FS 96 Nana / Emile Zola, 1955 (Box 1)
    Vertes, Marcel, 22 Jan 1955
    Vertes, Marcel, 28 Mar 1955
    Vertes, Marcel, engraving for Nana
  - FS 97 Ghost Stories / Walter de la Mare, 1955 (Box 1)
    de la Mare, Walter, 7 Feb 1955
    de la Mare, Walter, 8 Jun 1955
    Freedman, Barnett, 4 Jun 1955
    Freedman, Barnett, 13 Nov 1955
    Freedman, Barnett, 19 Aug 1956
    Freedman, Barnett, 16 Sep 1956
  - FS 98, 100 The Canterbury Tales, Volume I and II / Geoffrey Chaucer, 1955-1956; undated (Box 2)
    Coghill, Nevill, 10 Jan 1955
    Coghill, Nevill, 15 May 1955
    Coghill, Nevill, 12 Jan 1956
    Coghill, Nevill, 26 Aug 1956
    Coghill, Nevill, 14 Nov 1956
    Whyte, Edna, 30 woodcuts for Canterbury Tales
- 1957 publications
  - FS 99 Salome / Oscar Wilde, 1956 (Box 2)
    Ayrton, Michael, 25 Aug 1956
  - FS 100 The Canterbury Tales, Volume II / Geoffrey Chaucer, See 1956 publications: FS 98, 100 The Canterbury Tales, Volume I and II.
  - FS 101 Crime and Punishment / Fyodor Dostoyevsky, 1956 (Box 2)
    Rossem, Ru van, 6 Oct 1956
  - FS 103 The History of Mr Polly / H. G. Wells, 1955 (Box 2)
    Ribbons, Ian, 27 Sep 1955
  - FS 104 The Waterloo Campaign / Napoleon Bonaparte, 1956-1957 (Box 2)
    De Chair, Somerset, 24 Jun 1957
    Lachouque, Henry, 11 Nov 1956
  - FS 105 A Midsummer Night's Dream / William Shakespeare, 1957 (Box 2)
    Richardson, Sir Ralph, 10 Feb 1957
  - FS 106 Tales of Mystery and Imagination / Edgar Allen Poe, 1956 (Box 2)
    Ayrton, Michael, 2 Aug 1956
  - FS 109 Galley Slave / Jean Marteilhe, 1957 (Box 2)
    Fenwick, Kenneth, 18 Feb 1957
  - FS 110 Pride and Prejudice / Jane Austen, 1957 (Box 2)
    Church, Richard, 5 Apr 1957
- 1958 publications
  - FS 113 Vathek / William Beckford, 1957 (Box 2)
    Bawden, Edward, 27 Apr 1957
    Grimsditch, Herbert B., 27 Oct 1957
  - FS 115 The Adventures of Sherlock Holmes / Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, 1957; 1964 (Box 2)
    Conan Doyle, Adrian, 10 Mar 1964
    Hogarth, Paul, 24 May 1957
  - FS 116 The Third Crusade / Kennth Fenwick (ed.), 1957 (Box 2)
    Fenwick, Kenneth, 21 Jan 1957
    Hawthorn, Raymond, 19 Feb 1957
  - FS 117 Five Japanese Love Stories / Ihara Saikaku, 1957 (Box 2)
    De Bary, William Theodore, 8 Mar 1957
    Severin, Mark, 24 Apr 1957
  - FS 118 King Richard II / William Shakespeare, 1958 (Box 2)
    Scofield, Paul, 2 Feb 1958
  - FS 119 Pount Counter Point / Aldous Huxley, [1958?] (Box 2)
    Roseman, Leonard, [1958?]
  - FS 120 The Remarkable Life of Don Diego / Diego de Torres Villaroel, 1957-1958 (Box 2)
    Atkinson, William C., 7 Apr 1957
    Bennett, Harold J., 23 May 1958
    Bennett, Harold J., one wood engraving for Remarkable Life of Don Diego
  - FS 122 Sense and Sensibility / Jane Austen, 1958 (Box 2)
    Hassall, Joan, 6 Oct 1958
  - FS 124 The Book of the Thousand Nights and One Night / Powys Mathers (trans.), 1958 (Box 2)
    Martin, Frank, 20 Jul 1958
    Martin, Frank, 26 wood engravings for 1001 Nights
- 1959 publications
  - FS 125 The Trial of Charles I / Sir Thomas Herbert, 1958 (Box 2)
    Lockyer, Roger, 20 May 1958
    Wedgwood, Cicely Veronica, [1958]
  - FS 126 The Beach of Falesa / Robert Louis Stevenson, 1958 (Box 2)
    Bates, H.E., 9 Jul 1958
    Clarke Hutton, Thomas, 8 Apr 1958
    Clarke Hutton, Thomas, 9 Oct 1958
  - FS 127 The Struggle for Greece / Herodotus, 1958 (Box 2)
    Cavander, Kenneth, 16 Jan 1958
    Hawthorn, Raymond, 24 Apr 1958
    Meiggs, Russell, 31 Aug 1958
  - FS 128 The History of Tom Jones / Henry Fielding, undated (Box 2)
    Harris, Derrick, 30 wood engravings for Tom Jones, bound as booklet
  - FS 129 Love's Labours Lost / William Shakespeare, 1958 (Box 2)
    Rogers, Paul, 5 Jul 1958
    Sutcliffe, Berkeley, 1 Mar 1958
  - FS 130 Short Stories / Guy de Maupassant, 1958 (Box 2)
    Hopkins, Gerard, 21 Aug 1958
    Lambourne, Nigel, 28 Feb 1958
    Lambourne, Nigel, 3 drawings for Maupassant Short Stories
  - FS 132 Father Brown Stories / G.K. Chesterton, 1958 (Box 2)
    Ardizzone, Edward, 28 Apr 1958
  - FS 133 The Gold Rush / Edward Gould Buffum, 1958 (Box 2)
    Lewis, Oscar, 3 Jun 1958
  - FS 135 Mansfield Park / Jane Austen, [1958?]; 1964 (Box 2)
    Church, Richard, 21 Sep 1964
    Hassall, Joan, [1958?]
    Hassall, Joan, woodcut for Mansfield Park
  - FS 136 Astrophel and Stella / Sir Philip Sidney, [1959?] (Box 2)
    Hart, Kingsley, [1959?]
- 1960 publications
  - FS 137 The Golden Ass / Apuleius, 1958 (Box 2)
    Ayrton, Michael, 29 Nov 1958
  - FS 138 The New Newgate Calendar / Sir Norman Birkett (ed.), 1959 (Box 2)
    Birkett, Sir Norman, 3 May 1959
  - FS 142 The Taming of the Shrew / William Shakespeare, 1958-1959 (Box 2)
    Atkins, Robert, 20 Apr 1959
    Neama, May, 20 Jun 1958
  - FS 143 Hermsprong, or Man As He Is Not / Robert Bage, 1958-1959 (Box 2)
    Keeling, Cecil, 6 Oct 1958
    Keeling, Cecil, 14 Sep 1959
  - FS 144 Short Stories / O. Henry, 1959 (Box 2)
    Hogarth, Paul, 30 Apr 1959
  - FS 147 Northanger Abbey / Jane Austen, 1959 (Box 2)
    Hassall, Joan, 10 Jun 1959
  - FS 148 The Importance of Being Earnest / Oscar Wilde, 1959 (Box 2)
    Beaton, Cecil, 16 Dec 1959
- 1961 publications
  - FS 150 The Conquest of New Granada / Juan Rodriguez Freile, 1960 (Box 2)
    Atkinson, William C., 7 Apr 1960
  - FS 151 The Prisoner of Zenda / Anthony Hope Hawkins, 1960 (Box 2)
    Biro, B.S., 27 Mar 1960
  - FS 152 The Life and Death of Thomas Becket / George Greenaway (ed., trans.), 1960 (Box 2)
    Greenaway, George W., 7 Mar 1960
  - FS 153 The Adventures of Roderick Random / Tobias Smollett, 1960 (Box 2)
    Martin, Frank, 10 Apr 1960
    Martin, Frank, 39 wood engravings for Roderick Random
  - FS 154 King Richard III / William Shakespeare, 1950; 1959,; 1961 (Box 2)
    Hurry, Leslie, 5 Oct 1959
    Hurry, Leslie, 21 Aug 1950
    Seale, Douglas, 7 Apr 1961
  - FS 155 The Informer / Liam O'Flaherty, 1960; undated (Box 2)
    Ede, Charles, [1960?], draft of letter
    Lambourne, Nigel, 5 Jan 1960
  - FS 156 From Atlanta to the Sea / William Tecumseh Sherman, 1960 (Box 2)
    Jordan, K.C., 14 Mar 1960
    Liddell Hart, B.H., 11 Feb 1960
  - FS 157 Persuasion / Jane Austen, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
    Church, Richard, 21 Oct 1960
    Hassall, Joan, 18 Oct 1960
    Hassall, Joan, 17 Sep 1961
  - FS 160 The Sonnets of Michelangelo / Elizabeth Jennings (trans.), [1960 or 1961] (Box 2)
    Jennings, Elizabeth, [1960 or 1961]
  - FS 161 Fanny Burney's Diary / John Wain (ed.), 1961 (Box 2)
    Wain, John, 27 Dec 1961
- 1962 publications
  - FS 164 Les Liaisons Dangereuses / Pierre Choderlos de Laclos, 1961 (Box 2)
    Hawthorn, Raymond, 20 Feb 1961
  - FS 165 Lives of the Most Notorious Pirates / Charles Johnson, 1961 (Box 2)
    Lloyd, Christopher, 15 Oct 1961
  - FS 167 Almayer's Folly / Joseph Conrad, 1961 (Box 2)
    Clarke Hutton, Thomas, 29 Mar 1961
  - FS 169 Sonnets from the Portuguese / Elizabeth Barrett Browning, 1961-1962 (Box 2)
    Stone, Reynolds, 21 Apr 1961
    Stone, Reynolds, 30 May 1961, includes wood engraving affixed to letter
    Stone, Reynolds, wood engraving affixed to printed sonnet
  - FS 170 Tales from Two Pockets / Karel Capek, 1961-1962 (Box 2)
    Selver, Paul, 3 Sep 1962
    Svolinsky, Karel, 19 Aug 1961
    Svolinsky, Karel, drawing for Tales from Two Pockets
  - FS 171 A Short History of English Literature / Gilbert Phelps, 1962 (Box 2)
    Phelps, Gilbert, 27 Apr 1962
  - FS 172 The Natural History of Selborne
    - Correspondence, 1949; 1961-1962 (Box 2)
      Piper, John, 5 May 1949
      Piper, John, 13 Sep 1962
      Scott, W. Sidney, 10 Feb 1961
    - Artwork, undated (Oversize 1)
      John Piper, oversize drawing for Selborne
  - FS 173 Julius Caesar / William Shakespeare, 1961-1962 (Box 2)
    Harris, Margaret, 28 Oct 1962
    Shaw, Glen Byam, 19 Aug 1961
  - FS 175 Emma / Jane Austen, 1961-1962 (Box 2)
    Church, Richard, 6 Nov 1961
    Hassall, Joan, 18 May 1962
- 1963 publications
  - FS 178 At the Court of the Borgia / Johann Burechard, 1962 (Box 2)
    Parker, Geoffrey H.W., 13 Sep 1962
  - FS 180 Cheri / Colette, 1963; undated (Box 2)
    Jullian, Philippe, 10 Jun 1963
    Jullian, Philippe, seven engravings for Cheri
  - FS 182 Washington Square / Henry James, 1961 (Box 2)
    Lamb, Lynton, 13 May 1961
  - FS 184 Poems / Samuel Taylor Coleridge, 1963 (Box 2)
    Hough, Graham, 16 Mar 1963
  - FS 188 Julius Caesar / William Shakespeare, 1962 (Box 2)
    Lancaster, Osbert, 23 Aug 1962
  - FS 189 Shorter Works / Jane Austen, 1962-1963; undated (Box 2)
    Church, Richard, 8 Jun 1962
    Hassall, Joan, 26 Sep 1963
    Hassall, Joan, 5 Dec 1963
    Hassall, Joan, ten wood engravings for Jane Austen's Shorter Works
- 1964 publications
  - FS 192 The Twelve Caesars / Gaius Suetonius Tranquillus, undated (Box 2)
    Hawthorn, Raymond, drawing for Twelve Caesars
  - FS 193 Essays / William Hazlitt, 1963 (Box 2)
    Hampden, John, 28 Mar 1963
  - FS 194 The Brothers Karamazov / Feodor Dostoyevsky, 1962-1964 (Box 2)
    Hampden, John, 21 Aug 1963
    Lambourne, Nigel, 7 Oct 1962
    Lambourne, Nigel, pencil drawing for Karamazov
    Magarshack, David, 29 Apr 1964
  - FS 195 Poems / Andrew Marvell, 1963 (Box 2)
    Wedgwood, Cicely Veronica, 9 Jun 1963
  - FS 197 Crotchet Castle / Thomas Love Peacock, 1962-1963 (Box 2)
    Hopkins, Kenneth, 17 Oct 1962
    Reddick, Peter, 10 Dec 1963
    Reddick, Peter, 8 wood engravings for Crochet Castel
  - FS 198 Scott's Last Expedition / Captain R. F. Scott, 1963 (Box 2)
    Fuchs, Sir Vivian E., 16 Aug 1963
  - FS 199 Measure for Measure / William Shakespeare, 1964 (Box 2)
    Stone, Alix, 10 Apr 1964
- 1965 publications
  - FS 203 Jane Eyre / Charlotte Bronte, 1964 (Box 2)
    Colbert, Anthony, 10 Mar 1964
  - FS 205 Gulliver's Travels / Jonathan Swift, 1964 (Box 2)
    Bawden, Edward, 12 Nov 1964
    Bawden, Edward, 22 Nov 1964
  - FS 207 Scarlet and Black / Stendhal, undated (Box 2)
    Frank Martin, 13 wood engravings for Scarlet and Black
  - FS 209 Lives of the English Poets / Samuel Johnson, 1965 (Box 2)
    Hampden, John, 13 Mar 1965
  - FS 213 Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man / James Joyce, 1965 (Box 2)
    Masterman, Dodie, 11 Mar 1965
- 1967 publications
  - FS 232 Three Stories / Herman Melville, undated (Box 2)
    Palmer, Garrick, 8 wood engravings for Three Stories
  - FS 236 Colonel Jack / Daniel Defoe, undated (Box 2)
    Lawrence, John, 12 woodcutes for Colonel Jack
- Unidentified publications
  - [unnumbered] Tristram Shandy / Laurence Sterne, 1953; 1956 (Box 2)
    Harris, Derrick, 25 Sep 1956
    Harris, Derrick, drawings and layout for Tristram Shandy
    Stone, Reynolds, 7 Aug 1953
Index to correspondents and graphic materials
Ardizzone, EdwardFS 132
Atkins, RobertFS 142
Atkinson, William C.FS 120 FS 150
Ayrton, MichaelFS 33 FS 99 FS 106 FS 137
Bates, H.E.FS 126
Bawden, EdwardFS 8 FS 113 FS 205
Beaton, CecilFS 13 FS 148
Bennett, Harold J.FS 120
Birkett, Sir NormanFS 40 FS 138
Biro, B.S.FS 151
Bliss, Douglas PercyFS 45
Bonfils, RobertFS 41
Boullaire, JacquesFS 30
Braby, DorotheaFS 86
Brough, DianaFS 92
Buckland-Wright, JohnFS 11 FS 19 FS 26 FS 74, 76
Burton, RichardFS 71
Casson, Sir LewisFS 33
Cavander, KennethFS 127
Church, RichardFS 19 FS 110 FS 135 FS 157 FS 175 FS 189
Clarke Hutton, ThomasFS 22 FS 167 FS 126
Coghill, NevillFS 98, 100 FS 27
Colbert, AnthonyFS 203
Conan Doyle, AdrianFS 115
Darwin, BernardFS 62
De Bary, William TheodoreFS 117
De Chair, SomersetFS 104
de la Mare, WalterFS 97
du Maurier, DaphneFS 2
Ede, CharlesFS 155
Einzig, SusanFS 72
Fenwick, KennethFS 109 FS 116
Flint, Sir William RussellFS 87
Freedman, BarnettFS 97
Fuchs, Sir Vivian E.FS 198
Furse, RogerFS 71
Gaastra, JohnFS 63
Gibbings, RobertFS 30 FS 75
GoorFS 61